<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Forgetful :/</title>
    <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Forgetful :/</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Learning: Cassandra Best Practices at eBay</title>
      <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-cassandra-best-practices-ebay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-cassandra-best-practices-ebay/</guid>
      <description>https://www.ebayinc.com/stories/blogs/tech/cassandra-data-modeling-best-practices-part-1/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design News Feed System</title>
      <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-news-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-news-feed/</guid>
      <description>http://blog.gainlo.co/index.php/2016/03/29/design-news-feed-system-part-1-system-design-interview-questions/
Requirements Features  CRUD posts Comment on posts Share posts  What is in a news feed post?  Author Content Media (photos, videos, .etc) Comments and replies Operations:  CRUD Comment and reply on posts Share posts    What is on news feed page?  Sequence of posts Query or filter posts Operations:  Load more posts Delete posts I don&amp;rsquo;t want to see    Estimations (scale requirements)  How many users?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Approach a System Design Interview Question</title>
      <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-how-to-approach-a-system-design-interview-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-how-to-approach-a-system-design-interview-question/</guid>
      <description>The system design interview is an open-ended conversation. You are expected to lead it.
Step 1: Outline use cases, constraints, and assumptions. Gather requirements and scope the problem. Ask questions to clarify use cases and constraints. Discuss assumptions.
Question examples:
 Who is going to use it? How are they going to use it? How many users are there? What does the system do? What are the inputs and outputs of the system?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharding Pinterest: How We Scaled Our MySQL Fleet</title>
      <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-sharding-pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-sharding-pinterest/</guid>
      <description>https://medium.com/@Pinterest_Engineering/sharding-pinterest-how-we-scaled-our-mysql-fleet-3f341e96ca6f
TODO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Design Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>SQL or NoSQL SQL Tables vs NoSQL Documents SQL databases store data records in tables.
NoSQL databases store JSON-like field-value pair documents. Similar documents can be stored in a collection, which is analogous to an SQL table.
SQL Schema vs NoSQL Schemaless SQL Normalization vs NoSQL Denormalization SQL databases use foreign key to relate one table to another, which minimizes data redundancy.
We can use normalization in NoSQL, but this is not always practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Design Facebook Interview</title>
      <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-facebook-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-facebook-interview/</guid>
      <description>Guideline  Should not assume anything. Pin down the requirements, they&amp;rsquo;re looking for me to drive conversation. It should be my design, not half mine and half the interviewers. Try to cover both breadth and depth. Need to talk about both high level concepts and details associated.  What is Facebook looking for  They want to understand how I reason through a problem that I&amp;rsquo;ve not necessarily encountered before. They are looking to get signal on both my techincal and communication skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Design Topics</title>
      <link>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://murray-liang.github.io/forgetful/2020/02/design-topics/</guid>
      <description>Some high-level trade-offs  Performance vs scalability Latency vs throughput Availability vs consistency  Keep in mind that everything is a trade-off.
Performance vs scalability A service is scalable if it results in increased performance in a manner proportional to resources added. Generally, increasing performance means serving more units of work, but it can also be to handle larger units of work, such as when datasets grow.
Many algorithms that perform reasonably well under low load and small datasets can explode in cost if either requests rates increase, the dataset grows or the number of nodes in the distributed system increases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>